Who am I here with today?
My name is Dr. Shaquille O'Neal.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
A lot of them.
What were you doing prior to becoming a business mogul?
What was I doing prior?
I was killing your favorite NBA player.
You owned 155 Five Guys at one point.
I sold them.
You sold them?
Yeah, I sold them.
What's your secret to scaling in the franchise model,
or just businesses in general?
The secret to scaling is one word, delegation.
I can't be in 155 places at once,
but I know somebody that can.
So you're really good at bringing other people
in to run these businesses?
Yes, I am.
Did you come from a lot of money?
No, never.
What was the turning point to financial freedom for you?
The secret was just having special motivation.
My motivation was always being able
to give my mother what she wants.
Do you believe in God?
Of course.
Hey, my guy, you hungry?
Uh, yeah.
Go get a pizza.
All right.
I own it.
It's all yours.
You got it.
Yeah, take what you want.
Thank you.
No problem.
What was the most amount of money
that you've made in single year?
Guys, we just landed in Atlanta, Georgia,
and we are headed right now to interview Shaquille O'Neal,
who has a net worth of over $5,000.
500 million dollars.
A lot of you guys
have seen Shaq on TV commercials,
not only is he one of the greatest basketball players
of all time in the history of the NBA,
but he's also a business mogul, guys.
He owns hundreds of businesses all around the country.
So we're gonna be asking
him the secrets to his success
in becoming one of the greatest athletes ever
and how he became so wealthy outside of sports.
So with that being said,
let's go meet with Shaq and
see what he has to say.
Who am I here with today?
My name is Dr. Shaquille O'Neal.
And for those that don't know,
what industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
A lot of them.
DJing, law enforcement, and food and beverages.
Yeah.
Pizza.
And what were you doing
prior to becoming a business mogul?
What was I doing prior?
I was killing your favorite NBA player.
Let me ask you this.
You became one of the greatest athletes of all time,
not just basketball players,
one of the greatest athletes of all time.
What was the biggest driving factor
of success for you throughout your career?
I was a thief.
Let me explain.
If you see somebody that's doing better than you,
and you would like to aspire to be them,
steal what they're doing.
So for me, I stole Michael Jordan.
I stole Magic Johnson.
I stole Kareem Abdul-Jabbar.
I stole Muhammad Ali.
And I put it inside my brain,
and I created me, Shaquille O'Neal.
And you generated and made hundreds
of millions of dollars throughout your career.
There's a stat Sports Illustrated just did
that one in three NFL players
go broke within three to five years.
What's the best way to preserve that kind of wealth
when you're making a lot of money?
You get a lot of money dumped on you.
It's easy to make a lot of money,
it's hard to keep a lot of money.
How have you been able to
preserve hundreds of millions of dollars
of that money that you made throughout your career?
I think for those who are not financially literate,
learn this word, annuity.
Break that down for those that don't know it.
You need to look it up.
I know what annuity means.
He knows what annuity means.
But your homeowner can sign right now.
Look it up.
How many businesses do you own right now?
I have no idea.
And the reason I don't know how many I own,
because I know who you are,
and I know you're going to make us look good.
But let's just say I own a thousand businesses.
I don't want it to be edited like I'm bragging.
But I own a lot.
And across all of these, right?
In one year, in terms of revenue,
what was the most amount of money
that you've made in a single year?
You guys, we're about to get
right back to this interview with Shaq.
And it's about to get better and better.
But real quick, I've got a very
special announcement to make for you guys.
So one of the biggest questions I
get asked just about every single day
from you guys is how can I
connect with and get access to meeting
the type of people that you're interviewing,
the millionaires and the
billionaires that you're always interviewing?
And so for that reason, I
launched and created one of the biggest,
one of the greatest entrepreneur
communities in the entire world
called the School of Mentorship.
And that is where I host
live mentorship tours where every single week
I host live mentorship calls with the
biggest business owners in the entire world
from eight and nine figure
entrepreneurs to billion dollar company founders,
the people that exited and grew billion dollar networks
where you guys are able
to ask your questions about business,
about career advice, about life advice directly
to them on how you can become
business owners, entrepreneurs and successful people
just like the people that I interview.
Some of the people that we've had on these calls,
you can't even pay them for their time.
Some of them in the company,
they don't even know the value of their time.
And that's why we're here today with our host,
Steven Klubeck who became a
billionaire after selling his company
for $2.2 billion to Hilton.
He taught our community how to negotiate like a billionaire,
how to get access to capital
and find investors to help you start
and grow your business.
Or how about James Keyes,
who was the former CEO of two multi-billion dollar
Fortune 100 companies, Blockbuster and 7-Eleven?
He taught our community how
to become a CEO and leadership.
How about Cody Sperber who
runs four eight figure businesses?
He taught our community how to invest in real estate
without any money.
last three years and growing this channel to
over 10 million followers and most importantly building
a multi multi-billion dollar network of people that
i'm connected to it's that there's only one
shortcut to success and that is mentorship the only
way that you get from here to the place you
want to be is getting around the right people
and learning everything from them so that way you can
implement exactly the things that they teach you and
that's why for right now you can get access
to the millionaires and the billionaires that
i interview every week by joining this community
by going down to the link in the description of
this video i can't wait to see each and every one
of you guys inside of this community with that
being said let's get back to the video what was
the most amount of money that you've made in a
single year i have no idea because i don't do
anything for monetary purposes i'm just happy to be
blessed and i'm just happy to be alive and i'm
just gonna continue working i don't know how much
money i got in today's world do you think somebody
should start a business or franchise a business both
break that down i think you should start a
business if you're inspired by something and you want
to do something and you think it will work
and you believe it will work
well
you see something that's working you do it for
example on the campus of a business college i
think it'll work let's invest eight out of ten
companies they go out of business in five years
in today's world from your perspective what's the
most common mistake you see business owners make
in today's world the common mistake business owners
make is they think they know it all make
sure you hire people that are smarter than you so
what was the best advice you ever got from a
mentor well i got two pieces of advice one piece
of advice was to save 75 and have fun with 25
the other one was to hire people that are smarter
than me and you put at the table with some
hitters what's your best negotiation advice for
anybody in business don't talk first and start
high i'll start off with 200 million they'll be
like no 110 what about 140 what about 125 deal
if you started 50 and their budget is 200 you just
lost 150 million let me ask you this you own 155
guys at one point i sold them you sold them
yeah sober what's your secret to scaling in the franchise
model just businesses in general the secret to scaling
is one word delegation i can't be in 155
places at once but i know somebody there can you see that on your screen thanks for sharing you've created some greatelles for difference what you want to
say at the point where it's time in advance something we all want you to do is to miss some shoot onONup and get gathered into the halterшаun team
at once but I know somebody that can. So
you're really good at bringing other people in to run
these businesses? Yes I am. So I actually
learned that by winning championships. I know that you
know having great teammates is very important to
help you win championships. Yeah and did you come
from a lot of money? No never. What was the
turning point to financial freedom for you? Like how did
you know? I saw horror stories about
how five years after professional athletes start playing
they have nothing. I didn't want to be part of a
horror story so I had to teach myself. I made a
very big mistake. The first time I got a
million dollars I spent it in about 30 minutes. Bought
three cars, I bought three juries, and I bought
some suits because I didn't even know what FICO was.
And how long were you in the NBA for? 19
years. 19 years. What was the secret to that longevity? It's
one thing to make it to the league. 99% of
players that make it they weed out within two to three
years. How did you have 19 years of longevity
at the height of your game? The secret was just
having special motivation. My motivation was always being
able to get my mother what she wants.
I did that for as long as I could and of
course she has what she wants but after 19 years when
you can't get it, you can't get it. I was
a little bit more motivated. I was a little bit more
motivated. I didn't do the things that the young
people do anymore. You have to do something else.
Do you believe in God? Of course. How
important has faith been for you throughout your career?
Very important. None of this is possible without God.
What was the biggest risk you ever took in
business? Not pulling the trigger when I had
the opportunity to. Howard Schultz wanted to open
Starbucks at the hood so when he used the term
the hood I was thinking the hood but I didn't know
anything about you know re-gentrification and
re-beautification of you know certain areas and
I didn't pull the trigger. And then Magic Johnson
opened up I think 155 Starbucks. And among your
best friends, you're the most successful person in the
world. What is the one trait that you think
you have in common with the most successful people
that you study and know? What is that one trait
that they all have in common? I think they're
nice. I think they're humble and I think they have
great people around them and they keep it very
simple. Like Jeff Bezos said, you invest in things
that's going to change people's lives. I heard
him say that and I changed my whole investment
strategy and I've been very, very successful. Hey
my guy, you hungry? Yeah. Go get a pizza.
I own it. It's all yours. Yeah, take what
you want. Thank you. No problem. What's the number
one thing that you look for in people when you're
investing in a business? I like to believe in what
they believe in. Like for example, if you was
going to start this company and you came in with
those beautiful eyes and told me your passion, I
would definitely invest in you. I'm a big fan of
yours. How did you find the self-belief to
go make hundreds of millions of dollars throughout your
career? That's kind of a tricky question. I had
an athletic advantage where I was given a lot of
money to play sports and then I took that
money and leveraged it and did certain things. So I
could kind of answer that question, but I really can't
because for me it was all luck. Do you think
everybody's built for entrepreneurship? I think yes,
everybody is. And my final one for you,
somebody watching this right now,
they don't come from anything,
maybe they're at rock bottom, something bad just
happened to them. Give them a quick 60 second
blueprint, a couple pieces of advice to really
stick with them. They want to become Shaquille O'Neal
wealthy in today's world. If you have a plan,
write it down, figure it out. If somebody else
is already doing what you're doing, watch
them, steer what they're doing, add your razzmatazz
to it and you should be fine. But always
believe there will be ups and downs in this business.
The longer you believe, the quicker you'll make it
to the top. You got amazing advice, my friend.
I really appreciate you. It means a lot. Thank
you for, I got to come over here. Thank you,
my man. I appreciate you,
man. You guys, that's a wrap.
On today's video, we just interviewed Shaquille
O'Neal, one of the craziest interviews you can
possibly get in this game. Not only is he
one of the most famous people in the world,
but he's one of the greatest athletes of
all time and is now an absolute business mogul.
But I need everybody watching to like
and subscribe for amazing content we've got coming
very, very soon with the
world's leading entrepreneurs, athletes, celebrities,
business professionals. You do not want to miss
out on the content I have coming very soon.
And as I mentioned earlier, guys, everybody watching
needs to be a member of my private
entrepreneur community.
To get connected directly, to get
mentored directly from the millionaires and the
billionaires that I interview every single week in my
community. To join, go to the link in the
description of this video. I can't wait to see
on the inside of my community, these school of
mentors. But with that being said,
I'll see you in the next video.